CURRICULUM VITAE

PERSONAL DATA

Name : Francis Githua Mukui

Address : P.O. Box 54974-00200 Nairobi

Telephone : + 254713700070

Cell phone : +254721460676

Email address :fgmukui@gmail.com

QUALIFICATION PROFILE

Am a hard working self-motivated civil engineer able to adopt to new working environment and learn better techniques in order to achieve the organization's objectives. I have twenty-two (22) work experience in KEBS having worked in standards development, import inspection and Quality assurance departments. Eleven (11) years I've been in supervisory/ management / positions, seven (7) years as head of civil engineering section, one (1) year as acting head of quality assurance with six staff reporting to me in South Rift Region(SRR) and three years (3) as officer in charge ICDN with 28 staff reporting to me. I streamlined inspection activities at ICDN and oversaw the transformation and expansion of KEBS ICDN office from the time of metre gauge rail to SGR whereby more resources were acquired to handle increased cargo volumes.

CAREER OBJEVTIVE

To secure a higher management responsibility and more challenging position in my organization in order to fully utilize my technical experience and supervisory/management skills while making a significant contribution to achievement of the organizations objectives and this would also enable me to expand my knowledge and leadership skills.

PROFESSIONAL QUALIFICATION

- 1) Quality management systems (QMS) auditor
- 2) Gazetted inspector
- 3) Registered graduate engineer

WORK EXPERIENCE

PERIOD	INSTITUTION	KEY POSITIONS	KEY RESPONSIBILITIES	
	Kenya Bureau	Assistant Manager-	a)	Planning, organizing, coordinating and directing Quality
May	of Standards	Quality assurance		Assurance activities
1997-		(civil engineering)	b)	Facilitating implementation of Kenya Standards
Now		N. 0040 N	,	And Product certification marks
		Nov 2018 -Now	c)	Monitor implementation of work plans by evaluating
			.1\	inspections and performance reports
			d)	Reviews training needs analysis of staff
			e)	Evaluating staff performance as per the human resource
			f)	policy Participate internal quality audits, root cause analysis and
			''	implementation of corrective actions in line with the
				requirements of International standard ISO 9001.
			g)	Participates in departmental and technical meetings as
			9)	appropriate
			h)	
			,	the quality of service to customers
		Officer in charge-	a)	Planning, organizing, Coordinating, directing and managing
		ICDN	ĺ	Inspection activities
			b)	Supervise the enforcement and implementation of product
		Nov 2015- Oct		standards
		2018	c)	Planning and scheduling inspection of targeted products
				according to risk profiling
			d)	Coordinate internal quality audits, root cause analysis and
				implementation of corrective actions in line with the
				requirements of International standard ISO 9001.
			e)	· · · · · · · · · · · · · · · · · · ·
				with product specifications
			f)	supervising officers at the entry points through allocation of
				duties and ensuring that resources are available for
			۵)	operations Evaluating staff performance as per the human resource
			g)	policy
			h)	Participate in external stake holders meetings
		Acting Manager Quality assurance	a)	Planning, organizing, Coordinating, directing and managing
			α,	quality assurance activities
		Nov 2014- Oct	b)	Supervise the enforcement and implementation of product
		2015	/	standards and product certification
			c)	Assist in preparing quality assurance budgets
			ď)	Reviews training needs analysis of QA staff
			e)	Evaluating QA staff performance as per the human
				resource policy
			f)	Coordinate internal quality audits, root cause analysis and
				implementation of corrective actions in line with the
				requirements of International standard ISO 9001
		0 "	g)	Participate in technical and departmental meetings
		Quality assurance		
		officer	a)	Coordinating Civil engineering activities
		Oct 2004 Oct	b)	Facilitating implementation and enforcement of Standards
		Oct 2004 –Oct 2015	c)	Participating in development of Kenya standards
		Inspection officer	a)	Coordinating Civil engineering inspection activities
		Mar 2002- Sept	b)	Facilitating implementation and enforcement of Standards
		2004	c)	Participating in development of Kenya standards

		Standards officer May 1997 –Feb 2002	a) b) c)	Researching and drafting Kenya standards Holding Technical committee meetings for development of Kenya standards Educating industries on standardization and its importance
Nov 1996 – May 1997	Aqua terra consulting engineers	Site engineer	a) b)	Supervising the contractor on a water project in Tana river Writing daily site progress reports
May 1995- Nov 1996	Niazsons contractors	Site engineer	a) b) c) d) e) f)	Supervising construction of 22 medium size residential houses, Supervising sub-contractors and preparing their payment certificates Measuring volumes of work on site In charge of site administration, human resource and materials Writing daily progress reports Involved in the construction of a 48 km tarmac road in Tana river including survey and earthworks calculations

ACADEMIC QUALIFICATIONS

PERIOD	INSTITUTION	ACHIEVEMENT
1990-1994	University of Nairobi	BSc. Civil engineering -2 nd class honours
1988-1989	Chania High School	K.A.C.E. – 14 points, 3 Principles,1 Subsidiary
1984-1987	Mururia High school	K.C.E –Division 1 ,22 points
1976 - 1983	Ndarugu Primary School	CPE 29 points

OTHER COURSES ATTAINED

SI no.	Course	Trainer	Period
	High performance leadership	KIM	18 th -20 th March 2015
	Management development skills	MASMEC Ltd	21st-23rd Oct 2015
	Results-based project management	KIM	26 th -30 th April 2010
	Leadership development skills	ETCT	5 th -7 th Jul 2017
	HR for non HR training	Goodit International	8 th -10 th June 2016
	Project Management	KIA	3 rd -5 th Nov 1999
	Introduction to ISO 17065	KEBS	6 th -7 th May 2013
	ISO/IEC guide 65	PTB	6 th -7 th Nov 2006
	OHSAS	KEBS	10 th -11 th Nov 2014
	Introduction to structural Eurocodes	Moi University	14 th Feb 2012
	Statistical quality control	KEBS	25 th -27 th Aug 2008
	Training of trainers	KEBS	22 nd -26 th Jul 2013
	Implementation of ISO/IEC 17020	KEBS	24 th -26 th Feb 2016
	ISO 9001:2015 IQA Upgrading course	KEBS	5 th - 6 th Mar 2018
	ISO 9001:2008 Lead auditors course	KEBS	9 th -13 th Nov 2015
	Implementation of ISO 27001 ISMS	KEBS	17 th -19 th Nov 2014
	Internal Quality audit	KEBS	15 th -16 th Sep 2010
	Implementation of ISO 14001:2004	KEBS	13 th -14 th Nov 2014
	Root cause analysis	KEBS	29 th -30 th Sep 2015
	Conformity assessment	SGS	17 th -18 th Sept 2007
	Timber grading	MRPW	14 th -25 th May 2001

Investigations course	CID	2001
Report writing	KIA	1999
Bar code awareness	GS 1 Kenya	26 th -27 th May 2009
Integrated standardization course	KEBS	9 th Jan-27 th Feb 1998

Skills

- 1) Leadership
- 2) High work ethic
- 3) Self-motivation
- 4) Adaptability
- 5) Organizational skills
- 6) Team player
- 7) Decision making

Referees

1) Dr. Eng Zablon Oonge –Lecturer, University of Nairobi and former employer P.O. Box 30197-00100 Nairobi

Cell: 0720801680

- 2) Bernard Nguyo –Head of Quality assurance, Nairobi P.O. Box 54974-00200 Nairobi
- 3) Cyrus Wambari Regional Manager, South Rift Region P.O. Box 2138-20100 Nakuru